#### Personal details

### **Emmy Karangwa**

Computer Engineering option Network Engineering karangwaemmy10@gmail.com (+250) 783133033

https://www.linkedin.com/in/karangwa-emmy-44a21a177/

# **Summary of Qualification**

Detail-oriented computer engineer with 2+ years of expertise working with some programming languages such as html, css, JavaScript, Java, React.js, Laravel and Sql, I also have advanced skills in Network design, installation and troubleshooting I am a graduate in Computer and software Engineering option Network Engineering from University of Rwanda, College of Science and Technology. I am willing to learn new things. I focus on key inputs and produce good quality. I have good communication skills for interpersonal communication.

# **Work Experience**

## **Software Engineer**

December 2019–April 2020

Andela Kigali - Rwanda

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Developed a web application with my team, back end in Node.js, express.
- Developed a web application with my team, Front end in React.js, Redux.
- Developed testing methods of web application, where backend tested using Mocha and front end tested using Jest.
- Took courses on working in distributed teams and cross culture.

## **Key Achievements**

• Successfully developed product that could be taken to the marketplace.

## **Other Experience**

### **Class representative at University**

September 2015-November 2019.

University of Rwanda, College of Science and Technology.

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Keep a watch on the schedule for the entire semester and report/discuss with lectures for any modification required well in advance.
- speaking on behalf of all students on the Programme and not just giving my personal opinions.
- To ensure that students' views on academic matters are heard
- To ensure the University continually listens to and engages with students to improve teaching, learning, assessment and academic services.

#### **Lab Monitor**

June 2018 – July 2019.

University of Rwanda, College of Science and Technology.

# **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

Ц	Ensure to gather and distribute Project Description Forms and present them to the Lab
	Manager.
	Ensure to turn on equipment in morning and turn off in evening after work completion.
	Demonstrate and assist specific core hardware and software
	Provide support on base-level for computer network usage, access software.

### **Software Developer**

June 2018 – July 2019.

BICT (Broadcaster of ICT). University student association.

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- ☐ Organize programming boot camps.
- ☐ Facilitate learners during boot camps.

### **Education**

### Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Technology

*University of Rwanda, College of Science and Technology,* 

**Graduation**: 2019

**Relevant Coursework**: Computer Engineering Fundamentals, Wireless Communications & Networking, Software development, System analysis, design, development and testing, Computer maintenance.

#### Rwanda Advanced Certificate of Education

Kayonza Modern Secondary School

Period: 2012 - 2014, diploma in mathematics, physics and computer science (MPC).

# **Key Skills**

- System analysis, design, development and testing
  Deep Learning for network design, installation and troubleshooting.
  Computational Research & Development
  Programming with the following languages JavaScript, react.js, PHP, Laravel, html, css, NOde.js Express. DB: Sql, MySQL, Postgres and Mongo DB.
- ☐ Teamwork

### **Internship**

June 2018 – August 2018.

**Vision Technologies Company** 

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- ☐ Software and hardware maintenance
- ☐ Network Troubleshooting
- ☐ Network and CCTV camera installation
- ☐ Customer support

### **Certifications**

- Certified Bachelors of Computer and Software Engineering (CSE)
- IT essential and CCNA certificates.

# **Memberships**

• Association for Rwanda Younger Entrepreneurs (RYE)

## Languages

• English: Proficiency

• Kinyarwanda: Mother tongue

### **Hobbies**

• Reading, Writing, Gaming, Music, cooking.

#### References

1. **DR. Musabe Richard**, Dean of school of ICT in college of Science and Technology, university of Rwanda.

TEL: +250 789453014:

- 2. Apostle. Gasabira Emmanuel, Leader of Revelation Of Churches Family of God in Rwanda. TEL: +250 788649928.
- 3. Mr. Murangira Theoneste, Head of Department of Computer and Software Engineering in College of Science and Technology.

TEL: +250 785207523

I certify that the information given herein is true and complete to the best of my knowledge.